David Simduwa Alsina

 \mathbf{L} +34 685383075 | \mathbf{Q} Portfolio | \mathbf{Q} Barcelona, Spain.

Summary

I am a Master of Science in Geospatial Technologies, specialized in analyzing and processing spatial data using advanced technologies. With a background in geography and previous work experience, i have a solid knowledge of the principles of geographic information science and its applications in numerous fields such as disaster management and business development. My interests and experience focus mainly on the use of modern technologies in solving real world problems in the field of geosciences and information technologies. I have experience in the fields of business development, cartography, GIS, spatial statistics, IoT, front end software development and web design. I also have experience in other related fields such as remote sensing and land use.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Geospatial Technologies

Sep 2019 - Mar 2021

University of Münster, Universitat Jaume I, Universidade NOVA de Lisboa

Germany, Spain & Portugal

Development and application of computer-based solutions to solve spatially related problems from a global to regional scale, through interdisciplinary methods that bridge informatics and geosciences.

The Influence of (shifts in) Environmental Factors on Land-use Change in the Mekong Delta (1988 - 2009)

Masters thesis. Using a logistic regression approach to analyze how shifts in environmental variables (distance to river and sea, salinity, subsidence) have driven land-use change in the Mekong Delta between 1988 - 2009.

BSc Geography University of Maiduguri

Aug 2010 – Apr 2015

Niaeria

Understanding the principles of geography, how the different aspects of the environment relate and work together as a system. The role of geography in creation of a sustainable environment.

Analysing the effects of poverty on the environment, a case study of Maiduquri Metropolitan council

Bachelors thesis. Use of basic services such as good access roads, good drainage, waste disposal facilities etc. as factors to quantify environmental risk in neighbourhoods lacking those amenities in Maiduguri metropolitan council.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AnyTech365

Senior Support Technician

May 2017 - Present

Malaga, Spain

• Resolve hardware problems such as printing due to missing or corrupt drivers

- Resolve problems with corrupt windows updates and problems in installing windows updates
- Resolve application failures such as missing dll, missing framework etc.
- Reinstall and reconfigure operating system in the event of a system crash
- Perform data recovery when there is a system failure such as blue screen or corrupt boot configuration

Business Development / Personal Assistant to Chief Executive DATECH Nigeria limited

Jan 2017 – Apr 2017

Abuja, Nigeria

- Preparation of projected income statements to determine the profitability of potential business
- Carry out market survey of item cost, raw materials and potential profitable end cost of brand products
- Play a vital role in product planning and design (Including branding and packaging)
- Planning and organization of social media campaign to boost awareness of brand products
- location of suitable site for construction of factory for ease access to raw materials and distribution of finished products into the market
- Carrying out promotional and marketing activities to boost awareness of the brand products before and after they are launched in the market

GIS Technician Oct 2015 – Oct 2016

National Emergency Management Agency (NEMA)

Abuja, Nigeria

- Participated in the production of flood vulnerability map of Nigeria for the upcoming monsoon season.
- Registration of displaced persons in different parts of the country
- Participated in stakeholder meetings and production of the annual flood outlook bulletin
- Organisation of sensitisation walk to raise awareness during the international disaster risk awareness day

Update and maintain inventory of relief operations that are completed or ongoing.

GIS Intern Jun 2013 – Sep 2013

Federal Ministry of Environment, Department of Forestry

Abuja, Nigeria

- Drafting of letters for official purposes and writing minutes of official meetings
- Digitization and mapping of all forest reserves in Nigeria
- Organising sensitization walk on the importance of trees to the environment during the world environment day

RELEVANT SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, R, SQL, JavaScript

Database: PostgreSQL, PostGIS

GIS: ArcGIS Pro, ArcGIS Online, Collector, Survey 123, QGIS

Image processing: ERDAS Imagine, PCI Geomatica Web development: HTML 5, CSS, Wordpress, Bootstrap

Statistics: R, GeoDa, SPSS, Tableau Others: Microsoft office, Protégé, Bitrix

Developer Tools: Git, Visual Studio, Spyder, Jupyter, RStudio, Brackets

Libraries: GeoPandas, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, PySAL, Leaflet, scikit-learn, SciPy, Keras, Tensorflow, etc.

Organizational Skills

Motivational leadership course: AnyTech365

Malaga, Spain, 2019

Scrum Master Program Team: 12th Edition of GeoMundus Conference

University of Münster, Germany, 2020

LANGUAGES

Mother Tongue: English

Other Languages:

Spanish German
Reading Very Good Basic
Writing Very Good Basic
Speaking Very Good Basic

Honors, Funding and Awards

ErasmusPlus Scholarship Holder

2020

European Commission

STIBET I fellowship holder

2020

DAAD